# We're reindeer, we're not horses #
# 我们是驯鹿 我们不是马 #
# We're Santa's Flying Forces! Ho ho! #
# 我们是耶诞老人的飞行团队! 后后! #
Hut! Hut! Hut! Hut!
小屋! 小屋! 小屋! 小屋!
Hey!
喂!
Guys! Guys! We lost Santa!
小伙子! 小伙子! 我们把耶诞老人弄丢了!
That's better.
那更好
Julius, look!
朱利尔斯 你看!
It's Santa's Flying Forces!
它是耶诞老人的飞行团队!
- Not again!  - Yahoo!
- 又来了!  - 呀吼!
Oh, Niko! Be careful!
阿 尼科! 小心!
Whoa, whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
噢 噢! 噢 噢 噢 噢!
Whoa, whoa!
噢 噢!
Niko, look out!
尼科 注意!
Darn kid!
臭小子!
I think I know which one my dad is.
我认为我知道哪一个是我的爸爸
Don't tell me...
不要告诉我...
the one who flies the fastest, jumps the highest,
那个飞最快的人 跳最高的人
and has the most courage?
还是最勇敢的?
Did you see him too?
你也看见他了吗?
I'd do anything to be up there flying with my dad.
要是能与我的爸爸一起飞我愿意做任何事情
I know, I know.
我知道 我知道
But these things don't happen overnight. They take practice.
但是这些事情不可能一夜发生 他需要苦练
But I'm always practicing!
但是我总是在练习ㄚ!
Sure, but you gotta really believe in yourself.
当然 但是你必须真的相信你自己
Huh?
嗯?
I believe you can fly.
我相信你能飞
Now show me that you believe it.
现下让我看看你相信
That's my boy!
好样的!
Don't think, believe!
不要乱想 要相信自己!
Believe! Believe!
自信! 自信!
I don't believe it.
看来是我期望太高了
I almost flew this time, didn't I, Julius?
我几乎这次能飞 不是吗 朱利尔斯?
You sure did, Niko.
你当然能做 尼科
You sure did.
你当然能做
Hey, Niko...
嗨 尼科...
...was your daddy a chicken?
...你的爸爸是一支鸡吗?
'Cause you fly like a chicken!
因为你飞起来就像一支鸡!
My dad's on the Flying Forces!
我的爸爸是飞行团队的!
Yeah, and my dad's Santa Claus.
是的 我爸爸还是耶诞老人勒
Just you wait, or I'll...!
你等着瞧 否则我将...!
Remember how we deal with bullies?
还记得我们怎样对付混混的吗?
Chin up...
别灰心...
...and just ignore them.
...别理他们
My dad's a three-legged moose.
我的爸爸是一头三条腿的大角麋鹿
Yeah! And my daddy's a four-headed... ugh!
是! 以及我的爸爸 乃4支大角麋鹿之首... 喔!
Ugh!
喔!
Now, that's ignoring.
现在 这才叫不理它
I don't get it, Julius.
我不明白 朱利尔斯
If Dad's really on the Flying Forces,
如果爸爸真的是飞行团队
why can't I fly like him?
我为什么不能像他一样飞翔?
No one knows exactly why
没有人知道为什么
Santa's Flying Forces have the gift of flight.
耶诞老人的飞行团队有飞行才能
Maybe those boys are right.
或许那些男孩说的对
Maybe my dad isn't one of the Flying Forces.
或许我爸爸不是飞行团队
You're ten times as brave as those boys.
你比那些男孩勇敢10倍的
Just... pretend they're not there.
只不过... 假装他们不存在
- You're right, Julius.  - Thank you.
- 你说对了 朱利尔斯  - 谢谢
I'll go practice flying at Antler's Hill, where they can't see me.
我要去鹿角的小山练习飞行 在那里他们就不能看见我
Hey! That's not what I said!
喂! 那可不是我说的!
Come back here.
回来
If anyone heard you talking about going to Antler's Hill for flying practice!
如果有人听到你要去鹿角的小山 练习飞行那就糟了!
Are you going to Antler's Hill for flying practice?
你要去鹿角的小山练习飞行吗?
No! Definitely not! No way!
不! 当然不! 不可能!
- Can I come along?  - Would you?
- 我能一块去吗?  - 好吗?
No one is going anywhere for flying practice, least of all to...
任何人都不能到别处去练习飞行 尤其是去...
Antler's Hill!
鹿角的小山!
Antler's Hill?!
鹿角的小山吗?!
How many times have you been told, Niko?
我告诉你多少次 尼科?
Sneaking out of Home Valley is strictly forbidden!
偷偷溜出家的山谷之外 是严格禁止的!
Yes, sir.
是的 先生
Niko wasn't sneaking anywhere.
尼科没溜到任何地方
I asked him to come and help me...
我是要他来帮我...
Huh?
嗯?
...pick up my Aunt Sally. She hasn't been well.
...接我的姑母萨莉 她身体不大好
Aunt Sally!
萨莉姑母!
Huh?
嗯?
Everybody, this is my Aunt Sally.
大家好 这是我的姑母萨莉
I'd better be going now.
大家好 我现在最好赶快走
- I'll take you!  - Such a good boy!
- 我送给你!  - 真是个好男孩!
Let me get that for you.
让我为你弄好
All right, all right.
好 好
But it won't be so funny if the wolves see you.
如果让野狼看见你 它将不是如此有趣
We're only safe here in the valley as long as the wolves don't know it exists.
我们只要在这山谷里是最安全的 只要野狼不知道它的存在
That's why no one leaves Home Valley.
这就是没有人会离开山谷的原因
- Yes, sir.  - Yes, Dad.
- 是的 先生  - 是的 爸爸
You heard our leader.
你们听到我们领导人的话了
I don't want to hear any more talk of going to Antler's Hill.
我再也不想听到 谁要去鹿角的小山
Is that clear?
清楚了吗?
Okay, Julius.
好吧 朱利尔斯
Finally, I'm getting through to you.
终於 使你明白了
See you tomorrow at Antler's Hill!
明天鹿角的小山见!
Now, let's see. I'm sure I was supposed to take a right back there,
现在 我们看看我确信 我们应该退回去右转
and then a left,
然后左边
and then another left, and then a right.
然后在左边 然后右边
That means I should be back at the tourist bus right about...
那表示我们应该 在旅游巴士回到...
now?
现在?
Niko, stay still!
尼科 别动!
Mom, why does nobody believe that Dad is one of the Flying Forces?
妈妈 为什么没人相信 爸爸是飞行团队的?
Well, no one ever met him, apart from me.
嗯 从来没有人见过他 除了我之外
Tell me about Dad again.
再给我说说爸爸的事
Okay.
好吧
Ugh...
嗯...
Your dad was the handsomest reindeer in Santa's Flying Forces.
你爸爸是耶诞老人飞行团队里 最漂亮的驯鹿
That must be where I get it.
这点我一定遗传了爸爸
It was the day after Christmas,
那是在耶诞节之后日子
and I went out on my own looking for moss.
我独自走出去 寻找苔藓
Suddenly, the Flying Forces landed right in front of me.
突然 飞行团队 降落在我的面前
Santa's sleigh had broken down.
耶诞老人的雪橇坏了
And what happened then?
然后发生什么事?
That's when I met your dad.
我就在那时遇见你爸爸
He was a real daredevil,
他真是一位勇士
and once he'd fixed the sleigh, he took me for a spin.
他把雪橇修好 带我去兜圈子
It was magical!
太不可思议了!
Flying through the clouds high above the valley...
在高高山谷之间穿梭云间...
... but then he had to leave.
...然而最后他必须离开
After that, I never saw him again.
在那之后 我从未再见到他
If Daddy was so great,
如果爸爸如此伟大
how come he never came to visit his son?
怎么从不来 看看他的儿子?
Well, he never knew Niko here would be born that very next spring.
嗯 他不知道隔年 生了尼科
Who could know?
谁又能知道?
But why didn't you go and tell him?
但是你为什么没去告诉他?
Because he lives with the Flying Forces in Santa's Fell,
因为他和飞行团队住在 耶诞老人的家
and no one knows the way there.
没有人知道去的路
Don't you miss him?
你不想念他吗?
No. I have one man in my life, and he's quite enough.
不在我的生命里有一个男人 有他就足够了
Now, go to sleep, Niko.
现在 就寝罗尼科
Mom, what's Dad's name?
妈妈 爸爸的名字叫什么?
Good night, Niko.
晚安 尼科
More bad luck, boss.
更坏的运气 头家
No reindeer anywhere.
任何地方都没有驯鹿
We need reindeer.
我们需要驯鹿
We need food.
我们需要食物
I've got an idea, boss.
我有一种办法 头家
One word: moss.
一句话 苔藓
Huh? Huh? Huh?
嗯? 嗯? 嗯?
Reindeer eat moss. We eat reindeer.
驯鹿吃苔藓我们吃驯鹿
I'm simply cutting out the middleman.
仅去掉中间细节
Please yourself.
随你便
Our luck must change.
我们必须改改运气
Go out there, find food.
出去 找到食物
Find reindeer.
找到驯鹿
Aah!
啊!
Crash-landing maneuver.
迫降演习
Never know when you're gonna need it.
当你将要需要它时
I thought I'd find you here.
我认为我将在这里找到你
What do you have to say for yourself, young man?
你还有什么可解释的 年轻人?
You've got to help me.
你必须帮助我
I've been making a fool of myself all morning.
我整个上午都在当傻瓜
None of that! It's dangerous out here!
少来! 这里很危险!
Straight back to Home Valley with you.
我得赶紧和你回到山谷
Please?
求求你?
Oh, all right.
噢 好
But only for one minute.
但是只有一分钟
Maybe you don't have to fly.
或许你不必飞
Maybe you could glide.
或许你能滑动
It's really just falling, but slower.
只是坠落 但是更慢
Hey, I'm great at falling.
嘿 我擅长坠落
Good! Now, climb to the top of that tree and...
好! 现在 爬到那树上...
Are you crazy? Reindeer don't climb trees.
你发疯吗? 驯鹿不爬树的
That's just dumb.
那太愚蠢了
Wow! Are you really going to do it?
哇! 你真的要那么做?
Oh, yeah, and uh, don't try and stop me.
噢 是 噢 不要想办法停止我
Not bad.
坏不坏
Uh-huh!
噢!
Uhh!
啊!
Uhh... aaahhhh!
啊... 啊啊!
Now, that's a view.
现在 好美的景色
Breathtaking.
美极了
No wonder reindeer have been so hard to find.
难怪驯鹿 如此难发现
What are you on about, Specs?
你说什么 史贝斯?
They've started living in trees.
他们已经开始生活在树上了
Ugh.
啊
What?
怎么了?
Don't worry, Niko. I know you'll fly one day.
不要担心 尼科 我知道你有一天将会飞
Really?
真的吗?
You think so?
你这样想吗?
Sure.
当然
Wo...! Wo...!
哦...! 哦...!
Wolves!
野狼!
Run, kids!
快跑孩子们!
Aaahhh!
啊啊!
Oh, whoa!
噢 哼!
Aah aah aah!
啊 啊 啊!
Nah nah-nah nah-nah!
呐 呐 呐 呐 呐!
Look where you're going, boys.
看你将去哪儿 孩子们
Ow! Guhh...
喔唷! 啊...
They shouldn't be able to find our tracks now.
现在他们应该不能 找到我们的踪迹
Come on, Saga. We've got to warn the herd.
跟我来 传奇 我们必须警告鹿群
Wolves!
野狼!
- Hey?  - Wolves! Wolves!
- 喂?  - 野狼! 野狼!
- What's going on?  - Wolves! We saw them!
- 发生什么事?  - 野狼! 我们看见他们了!
Niko, I thought I told you to...
尼科 我认为我告诉你了...
Are you sure they didn't follow you?
你确信他们没跟踪你吗?
Yes, Grandpa, we lost 'em.
是的 爷爷 我们甩掉他们了
Are you absolutely certain?
你绝对肯定吗?
Black Wolf will be pleased.
头家狼准高兴的
Come on, Specs, let's eat!
来吧 史背 我们开吃!
You go ahead. I'm stuffed. Just had some moss.
你继续 我好撑 刚吃了些苔藓
Woohoooooo!
喔!
Ohhh!
哦!
Defensive formation.
防御队形
Men on the outside, women and children on the inside. Hurry!
男人在外面上女人小孩在里面 赶快!
Children! Stay together, children.
孩子们! 孩子们 待在一起
Kids, stay close to your mothers.
孩子们 靠拢妈妈
Children, together.
孩子们镇静
Keep it moving! Come on! Keep it moving!
动起来! 跟我来! 动起来!
Keep in! Keep in!
待里面! 待里面!
Emergency evacuation!
紧急撤退!
Run!
跑!
Dad!
爸爸!
Come on! Hurry up!
跟来! 赶快!
Dad! Come on!
爸爸! 跟我来!
Hey, you let 'em get away.
喂 你让他们跑了
Niko! Thank goodness you're okay.
尼科! 谢天谢地你没事
What's going on?
发生什么事?
Everyone, stay calm.
每一人 保持镇静
Who left the valley and led the wolves to us?
是谁离开山谷 引来野狼的?
I...
我...
I was sure they didn't follow us.
我确信他们没跟踪我们
Flying practice again, was it?
又是飞行练习 是吗?
Look what your silly dream has cost us...
看吧你的傻梦 已经带来我们恶梦...
our home, and very nearly our lives.
我们的家 以及我们的生活
That's enough!
够了!
He's just a boy. He didn't mean for any of this to happen.
他只是一个孩子他也不想为这事发生
Hmph.
哼
The wolves will come back,
野狼将回来
and when they do, there will be many.
他们来时 将会一整群
We must keep moving.
我们必须继续走
Oona is right.
乌纳是正确的
We have to keep moving.
我们必须继续走
Where to, I do not know.
到那里 我不知道
I don't know what to do with the boy, Julius.
我不知道该拿这男孩怎么办 朱利尔斯
He just doesn't listen.
他就是不听话
He'll grow out of it, Miss Oona.
他长大就 乌纳小姐
From now on, there will be no more mention of his father
今后 别再提到他父亲
or of flying lessons.
或者飞行课
He just has to forget all that.
他必须忘记所有
That boy Niko is a jinx!
那个男孩尼科是个克星!
Unreliable!
不可靠!
How can you trust a boy who thinks he can fly?
你怎能相信认为他能飞的人?
I know. If only I hadn't gone with Niko,
我知道 要是我没和尼科一起去该多好
then we'd still have a home.
然后我们就不会失去家园
I don't want you playing with Niko again.
我不想要你 再次和尼科玩了
Next time he might bring death to us all.
下次 他可能把我们全部害到都死掉
No wolves to be seen.
没有看见野狼
Where's Niko?
尼科在那里?
- Niko!  - Niko!
- 尼科!  - 尼科!
- Come on! Niko?  - Niko, where are you?
- 快点尼科?  - 尼科 你在那里?
- Niko's gone!  - Niko?
- 尼科已经走了!  - 尼科?
We have to go back and find him.
我们必须回去找到他
I'm sorry, Oona, but we must continue.
对不起 乌纳 但是我们必须继续走
Otherwise, the wolves will track us down.
否则 野狼 将会追上我们
Please, Dad, we have to find Niko.
求求你 爸爸 我们必须找到尼科
I'm not leaving without my son.
找不到我儿子 我决不离开
No one leaves the herd!
谁都不准离开鹿群!
What if the wolves find your tracks?
如果野狼找到你的踪迹 怎么办?
- But...  - You'll bring them down on us.
- 但是...  - 你会把狼群引来的
We'll all die.
我们全部都会死
He's right, Miss Oona.
他是对的 乌纳小姐
This is a job for me.
这是我的工作
I can avoid the wolves by flying
我能透过飞 来避开野狼
and spot the boy from the air.
能从空中找到他
You must promise to bring him back, Julius.
你必须许诺 把他带回来 朱利尔斯
Don't you worry about a thing.
你不必担心
Niko!
尼科!
Niko! Wait!
尼科! 等等!
Ah. So... where we going?
啊 因此... 我们要去哪?
I'm going to Santa's Fell.
我要去耶诞老人的家
I'm spending Christmas with my dad.
我要与我爸爸一起过耶诞节
Great idea.
极妙的想法
Really? You think so?
真的吗? 你这样想吗?
Sure! Only...
当然! 只是...
Well, there is one small detail.
嗯 有一个小的细节
Nobody knows where Santa's Fell is.
没人知道耶诞老人的家在那
So... why don't we go back to the herd and ask around,
因此... 我们为什么不回去鹿群那 打听一下
and maybe someone might know.
或许某人知道
I know where it is.
我知道它在那里
Really?
真的?
The Flying Forces always disappear behind that big fell on their way home...
飞行团队总是消失 在他们回家路上的大瀑布后面...
Hey! So does the moon, big guy!
嘿! 月亮也是!
...which means Santa's Fell must be on the other side of it.
...哪个表明耶诞老人的家一定 在它的另一边
Nonsense!
胡说!
I have to be strict with you, young man.
我必须对你严格了 年轻人
I'm drawing this line here, and if you cross it...
我在这画条线 如果你跨过它...
I will...
我将...
Fine! But you're on your own, Niko.
好! 但是你是一个人 尼科
I'm leaving.
我离开了
You hear that?
你听到了吗?
That's me, leaving.
那是我 要走了
Leaving, leaving, leaving.
走了 走了 走了
Good!
好!
'Cause I'm a jinx, and I'm unreliable.
因我是个克星 并且我不可靠
- Uhh...  - You're better off without me.
- 啊...  - 你离我远点 比较好
Huh?
嗯?
Oh.
噢
Then again... Santa's Fell?
然而... 耶诞老人的家吗?
Are you kidding me? I've always wanted to go there.
你跟我开玩笑吗? 我总是想要去那里
Lots of toys, right?
许多玩具 是吗?
And elves!
以及小精灵!
Who doesn't love elves?
谁不爱小精灵?
Doggies!
小狗!
I'm saved!
我得救了!
How do you lose a whole herd of reindeer?
你怎会没看见一整群驯鹿?
Those reindeer are meanies, boss.
那些驯鹿 太恶毒了 头家
I mean, look at poor Smiley. They nearly crushed him to death.
我的意思是 看看可怜的笑脸符 他们差点把他整死了
What I need's a miracle with this lot!
与这批一起干活 需要奇迹!
Oh, am I glad to see a friendly face.
噢 我好高兴 看见一张友好的脸
Huh?
嗨?
Hi! How do you do?
喂! 你好?
- I'm Essie. Nice to meet you.  - Wow!
- 我是埃西 很高兴见到你  - 哇!
You would not believe what I've been through.
你将不相信我经历哪些事
One minute I'm minding my own business while the owners go skiing,
一分钟我主人滑雪时 我还在考虑自己的事
next minute it's like, Hello! Where are all the signs?
下分钟就好像 你好! 那些标志在那里?
I must have been wandering around for days.
我一定是在外徘徊好几天了
Be a sweetheart and fetch me some water.
作一个好人 为我拿一些水吧
I am dry as a bone.
我都渴成骨头了
Is he a little simple in the head?
他脑里头是否缺根筋?
Poor pooch.
可怜的狗狗
You're no pooch.
你不是狗狗
You're... a wolf.
你是... 一匹野狼
And you're a marshmallow,
而你是一颗小软糖
sweet and tasty.
甜和可口
# We're reindeer, we're not horses #
# 我们是驯鹿 我们不是马 #
# We're Santa's Flying Forces! Ho ho! #
# 我们是耶诞老人的飞行团队! 后后! #
I hate it when they do that!
当他们做那时 我憎恶它!
But the Flying Forces are nice, and don't eat anyone.
但是飞行团队是好的 且不吃任何人
They help Santa bring presents to all the children,
他们帮助耶诞老人帮孩子带来礼物
and if you'd stop being naughty and become nice,
并且如果你将停止顽皮 且变成好的
Santa might give you a job too, and then...
耶诞老人也许可给你一个工作 然后...
then you'll get plenty of food.
然后你将得到足够的食物
Much better than eating me.
比吃我更好
Right?
是吗?
Flying Forces?
飞越团队吗?
Santa Claus?
耶诞老人吗?
Presents?
礼物吗?
That's it.
就是这样
Nobody touches the marshmallow.
谁也不行碰软糖
She's given me an idea.
她已给我一种想法
She's our lucky charm.
她是我们的吉祥物
We're moving out.
我们要搬出去
Next stop, Santa's Fell.
下一站 耶诞老人之家
Let's... let's, uh, take a break, huh?
让我们... 这样 噢 休息一下 吗?
Whew!
哎呀!
The Flying Forces!
飞行团队!
We're almost there! Yes!
马上就到了! 耶!
But...!
但是...!
But...
但是...
I was... so sure.
我是... 如此确信
Whew.
嘘
You did your best, Niko.
你尽力了 尼科
At least you tried.
至少你试过了
No one will ever be able to say we gave up.
没有人能说我们中途放弃了
Hey! I thought we were giving up!
喂! 我认为我们放弃了!
Almost!
差不多了!
Whoo, yeah!
哇 耶!
# Ain't no point in looking back #
# 后悔是没有意义的 #
# So they tell me #
# 他们这样告诉我 #
# Though I know this to be true #
# 虽然我知道这是真实的 #
- # I've been tossing... #  - Are you... okay, madam?
- # 但我一直迟疑... #  - 你是... 好 夫人?
Miss Wilma.
威尔玛小姐
And, yes, I'm fine.
并且 是 我好的很
But... you're trapped.
但是... 你被夹住了
I'm not trapped!
我没被夹住!
I'm just resting.
我只是在休息
What?
哇?
Whoa!
嗯!
What did you have to go and do that for?
你为什么这么做?
Hey! We just saved your life!
喂! 我们刚刚救你的命!
Exactly!
完全正确!
Now I have to save both your lives before we're even.
在我们扯平之前 我也会救你们的命
This is just great.
那太好了
I'm already late for a big gig in the South.
对於在南方的一场大的爵士音乐会 已经赶不上了
And you thought hanging upside down was going to speed things up?
你倒挂在树上 会使思考加速吗?
Maybe I'll just have to save his life twice.
或许 我救他的命两次就行
Don't worry, Wilma.
威尔玛 不要担心
You don't have to save our lives.
你不必救我们俩的命
We're heading north, anyway.
无论如何 我们要去北方
That's west, Captain Compass.
那是西方 罗盘船长
That's north.
那才是北方
Hmph!
哼!
"That's west, Captain Compass.
"那是西方 罗盘船长
That's north."
那才是北方 "
Hmph!
哼!
You know, Niko, that foolish weasel can teach you one important lesson:
知道吗 尼科 那支傻鼬 教你一门重要的课
those who can't read nature will be beaten by nature.
不懂自然的人 最后将被大自然打败
- Read?  - That's right.
- 是吗?  - 是的
Take that cloud over there, for instance.
就拿那边的云 给你举例
Now, what could that mean?
现在 那代表什么?
That a storm is coming?
风暴雪将要来吗?
A common mistake!
常识性错误!
No, that particular type of cloud is harmless.
不 那种类型的云 无害的
What it means is...
它的意思是...
Uh!
噢!
No need to be afraid, Niko!
没有需要害怕 尼科!
It's just a gust!
只是一阵狂风!
It'll blow over... before you know it!
我快被吹走了... 在你发现之前先告诉你!
Ahh!
啊!
Julius!
朱利尔斯!
I don't want to sound gushy or anything, but I just want you to know...
我不想显得很伤感或怎样 但我只想要你知道...
Yes?
是吗?
I would never eat you.
我绝不会吃你
That's... sweet.
真是... 体贴ㄚ
Yeah.
是ㄚ
I'm hungry!
我饿死了!
And I'm sick and tired of walking!
我累的不想走了!
Listen up, men.
听着 老兄
For years, we've been forced to hunt and scavenge for our next meal.
多年来 我们被迫打猎 且为我们的下一顿饭伤脑筋
Well, no more, thanks to our new lucky charm here.
嗯 今后不再这样了 感谢我们这位吉祥物
Hey! Go on, Essie!
喂! 继续 埃西!
I have had an idea that will change our lives.
我已经有一种想法 那将改变我们的生活
We're going to Santa's Fell.
我们要去耶诞老人之家
And we're going to feast on his flying reindeer.
我们他的驯鹿吃掉
And by eating our enemies,
吃掉我们的敌人
their strength will become ours.
他们的团队将成为我们的
You will be Santa's Flying Wolves.
你将是耶诞老人的飞狼队了
Ahem.
啊
Um...
嗯...
maybe I'm barking up the wrong tree,
或许我不该说这样的话
but if you eat Santa's reindeer,
但是如果你吃耶诞老人的驯鹿
don't you think he might just be a little bit upset?
你不认为他有 一点难过吗?
True.
也对
That's why we're going to eat Santa too!
所以我们把耶诞老人也吃掉!
And I'll take his place.
我将取代他的位置
Just think of all the delicious little boys and girls
请想起那些美味的小男孩和女孩
waiting for me to visit.
等我去拜访
But... but Santa's supposed to give children presents,
但是... 但是耶诞老人应该 给小孩礼物
not eat them!
而不是吃他们!
New Santa, new rules.
新耶诞老人 新规矩
Next stop, Santa's Fell.
下一站 耶诞老人家
- Huh?  - Huh?
- 嗯?  - 嗯?
I was just leaving!
我正要离开呢!
Get him!
抓住他!
Aaahhh!
啊!
Niko!
尼科!
Where are you?
你在那里?
Huh?
蛤?
Niko! Boy, am I glad to see you!
尼科! 哎哟 看见你真高兴!
Whoaaa!
哇!
Can't I leave you alone for five minutes?
我离开你 1分钟你就闯祸了?
They're gaining on us!
他们在追我们!
Faster, Niko!
快点 尼科!
You fly!
你飞走!
- Save yourself!  - I'm not leaving you alone again.
- 自己逃命去!  - 我不会再丢下你了
You only make things worse!
你只会给我添麻烦!
- Oh, no!  - Uh-oh!
- 噢 不!  - 噢噢!
The reindeer knows too much.
这支驯鹿知道太多了
No survivors.
别留活口
- My public!  - What?!
- 大家!  - 什么?!
Hmm?
嗯?
My first number is guaranteed to bring the house down.
我保证会让全场 博得满堂喝采
# Well, there's something that I want to say #
# 好的 有些事情 我想要说 #
# And there's something that I've got to do #
# 有某事情 我必须做 #
Oh, goodie! I love a good knees-up!
噢 好呀! 我好爱活跃演唱会!
Really? Me too.
真的吗? 我也是
Oh. This seat's free, miss.
噢 这个位子没人 小姐
# Even got down on my knees to pray #
# 甚至让我下跪祈祷 #
# 'Cause, baby, I miss you #
# 因为 宝贝 我想念你 #
# Whoo! #
# 喔! #
Oh!
噢!
Whoo! Whoa!
喔! 哼!
I'll drive, old-timer!
我来驾驶 老头!
Jump high, reindeer boy!
跳起来 小驯鹿!
# Dah dah doo-dah doo-dah doo-dah whoo! #
# 哒 哒 哒 哒! #
Aaahhhh!
啊啊!
Aaaahhhhhhh!
Ohh! The tree!
噢! 树!
Watch out for the tree!
留意树!
I see it! Backseat drivers!
我看见它了! 后座司机!
Whoa!
喔!
Whoo! Yeah!
噢! 耶!
Oh, here we go!
噢 开始了!
Ohhh!
噢!
Whoo-hoo!
喔吼!
Whoo whoo whoo whoo!
喔 喔 喔 喔!
Huh. Whew!
啊  哎呀!
I can't believe I got out of that without a single scratch.
真不敢相信 我逃出来了
Oh!
噢!
Nice going, Nutboy!
做的好 松果男孩!
Nutboy?
松果男孩?
Aah! My legs! I can't feel my legs!
啊! 我的腿! 我的腿没感觉了!
What the heck are you doing?
你到底在做什么?
All right, sorry!
喔 抱歉!
Keep your hair on!
你的毛还是那么帅!
The reindeer boy must be destroyed!
我一定要杀了那支小驯鹿!
Uh-uh!
噢噢!
Only room for one up here, missy!
只够一个人坐这里 小姐!
Is that the gratitude I get for saving your furry hide?
这就是救了你这多毛的 报答吗?
What do you mean, saving my handsome hide?
你意思是什 就了多帅的我?
I had the situation perfectly under control.
当时情势完全在我控制下
Well, that's the last time I'll save your...
好吧 那是我最后一次救你...
Hey! I said "furry," not "handsome."
喂! 我说"多毛" 不是"多帅"
Okay. So you saved our lives, and now we're quits.
好吧那你救了我们 现在我们扯平
I suppose you'll want to be on your way now.
我认为你现在想一个人 呆着吧
Huh!
哼!
You don't have to go.
你不必走的
I know when I'm not wanted.
我知道你们不需要我了
Let's go, Niko. Santa's Fell is that way.
尼科 让我们去 耶诞老人之家要往这边走
Oh, and before I go, Santa's Fell is that way.
噢 在我走之前 耶诞老人之家是要往这边走
Hey! Don't listen to her. She's totally unreliable.
喂! 不要听她 她可靠不住
- You know the way to Santa's Fell?  - Yep.
- 你知道耶诞老人家的路吗?  - 是
- Used to work there.  - Wow.
- 过去常常在那里工作  - 哇
Did you hear that, Julius?
你听到那了吗 朱利尔斯?
You really think we believe that?
你真认为我们会相信吗?
Hmph.
嗯
You gotta come with us.
你必须与我们一起来
The wolves are going to eat Santa and his Flying Forces!
那群野狼打算吃 耶诞老人和他的飞行团队!
What?! When... when were you going to tell me this?
什么?! 你打算... 什么时候 告诉我这事?
Calm down. No wolf ever made it all the way up to Santa's Fell.
冷静点没有野狼可到耶诞老人的家
- Ciao, boys.  - Please!
- 再见 男孩  - 拜托!
We need you! We'll do anything!
我们需要你! 你要我们做任何事都行!
Huh?
嗯?
Anything?
任何事情吗?
Don't get used to the view, missy.
小姐 别习惯看风景
This is strictly a temporary situation.
这只是暂时情势
So... have you ever met the Flying Forces?
因此... 你有见过 飞行团队吗?
Oh, yeah, lots of times.
噢 是 许多次
- Whoa!  - Whoa!
- 哇!  - 哇!
Can't you keep your hands off me for one second?
你可不可别碰我一秒?
Madam, please!
夫人 拜托!
My dad's in the Flying Forces!
我爸爸在飞行团队中!
Maybe you've met him.
或许你已经见过他
Really? Your dad's one of those guys?
真的吗? 你的爸爸 在那些人之中?
Uh-huh.
嗯哼
What do you mean, "one of those guys"?
你意思是什么 在那些人之中?
Oh, n-nothing.
噢 没有什么
I just never thought of them as the daddy types.
只不过我未想过他们 也会当爸爸
- What's your dad's name?  - I don't know yet...
- 你的爸爸的名字是什么?  - 我还不知道...
...but he's going to teach me how to fly.
...但是他会教我 怎样飞
Oh, they love their flying.
噢 他们喜爱飞行
It seems like that's all they do.
好像是他们能做的事情
I've taught Niko all the flying exercises he needs to know.
我已经教过尼科 所有飞行需要的练习
Really? Have you taught him launching leaps? Hmm?
真的吗? 你有教他 起飞跳跃吗? 嗯?
Or breathing short bursts?
或是瞬间短冲?
Or using hooves for improved aerodynamics?
或者使用蹄子 使空气产生动力?
Wow! Real flying exercises!
哇! 真正的飞行练习!
I'll be keeping an eye on you, missy.
我会盯注你的 小姐
Really?
真的吗?
Will you, now, Julius? Hmm?
是吗 现在 朱利尔斯? 嗯?
No!
不!
And the name's Nutboy! I mean Julius!
我的名字是松果男孩! 我意思是朱利尔斯!
I mean!
我意思是!
Oh, shut up!
噢 闭嘴!
Wolves!
野狼!
Isn't there a faster way, Wilma?
这是捷径吗 威尔玛?
Well, the shortcut across the River of Certain Doom
嗯 这是通过审判河的捷径
is just around the corner.
就在拐弯那边
River of Certain Doom?!
审判河?!
Okay, this is it!
好 就是它!
That's nothing!
什么也没有啊!
Okay, here's the plan.
好 计划是这样
Run!
跑!
- Hurry, men!  - That's it, Niko! Jump!
- 老兄 赶快!  - 尼科! 跳!
Aah! Aahhh...
啊! 啊啊...
Go for it! Come on! That's it, Niko. You can do it!
跟我来! 那是它 尼科你能做到的!
Nice going, Niko...
做的好 尼科...
and a heck of a plan, Julius.
让你的计画见鬼去吧 朱利尔斯
The River of Certain Doom was a piece of cake.
审判河只是一块蛋糕
That was the Trickle of Tranquility.
那是一条平静的小河
This is the River of Certain Doom.
这 河确信毁灭
How...
怎样...
how do we get across?
我们怎样通过?
Across the bridge, of course.
穿过桥 当然
Or not.
否则
All aboard! We have to fly across!
各位 都上来啦! 我们必须飞过去!
Are you nuts?
你脑壳坏啦?
I'll do the flying exercises Wilma taught me.
我会按照威尔玛教我的 飞行锻链
What's all this Wilma stuff? Don't you listen to me anymore?
威尔玛教你什么? 你没再听我吗?
I do, Julius! You always say I can fly.
我听 朱利尔斯! 你总是说我能飞
That's different! This is for real!
那不同! 这是真的!
Aaah!
啊!
I can fly! I can fly!
我能飞! 我能飞了!
It's working! It's working! It's...!
成功了! 成功了! 成...!
Oh nooooooo!
噢 不!
That's the end of reindeer boy.
小驯鹿玩完了
Looks like you bring us luck after all, marshmallow.
看起来你还是为我们带来好运 小软糖
Poor kid.
不幸的孩子
Come on. We have to find another way across.
跟我来 我们必须找到过去的路
There's a meal waiting at Santa's Fell.
耶诞老人的家 有一顿美食等着我们
Aaaahhhh!
啊!
Whoooaaaa!
哇!
Niko, get up!
尼科 起来!
Hurry!
赶快!
Oh, no! Look!
噢 不! 看!
Niko! Niko! Can you hear me? Ohh!
尼科! 尼科! 你能听到我吗? 哦!
Hurry, Julius, hurry!
赶快 朱利尔斯 赶快!
Uh, right! Rocks! We're going to need rocks!
噢 对了! 岩石! 我们需要岩石!
No! Too big! Too small!
不! 太大! 太小!
Niko's in mortal danger, and you're insulting rocks?
尼科有生命危险 你还在挑剔石头吗?
On my signal...
听我指挥...
three, two, one.
三 二 一
Now!
现在发射!
Niko!
尼科!
Niko! Niko!
尼科! 尼科!
- Oh!  - Unh.
- 噢!  - 啊
No!
不!
Oh oh oh!
噢 噢噢!
He's alive! He's alive!
他活着! 他活着!
Oh.
噢
Nice work, Nutboy.
干得好 松果男孩
Uh, you too. Whatever.
噢 你也是随你怎么说吧
Come on. We can't just lie around here all day.
跟我来 我们不能整天躺在这
I think somebody does need to lie around here all day.
我认为某人确实需要 整天躺在这
Specs?
史贝斯?
Huh?
嗯?
Do you really think Black Wolf will eat Santa and his Flying Forces?
你真的认为布莱克黑狼 将吃耶诞老人和他的飞行团队吗?
Well, you know,
嗯 你知道
doing bad things is kind of a tradition for us wolves.
做坏事对我们野狼来说 是一种传统
But we're not all like that... nasty, I mean.
但是我们一点也不象那样... 肮脏 我意思是
Some of us just look that way.
我们中有一些人看起来像坏蛋
Hey, do you think you could make me look like less of a bad guy?
喂 你觉得有办法让我 看起来不像一个坏蛋吗?
Hmm, let's see.
噢 让我想想
You can start by wagging your tail.
你可以从摇尾巴开始
Okay.
好吧
Come on, tail!
加油 尾巴!
Wag!
摇摇!
Talking to your tail again, Specs?
又再对你的尾巴说话了 史贝斯?
Huh?
嗯?
Oh!
噢!
Hey, Nutboy! Who are your friends?
喂 松果男孩! 你的朋友是谁?
Oh... nobody.
噢... 没人
Aren't you going to introduce me?
你不打算把我 介绍给大家吗?
Well...
好...
that's my Aunt Sally
那是我的姑母萨莉
and that's my wife and that's...
那是我的妻子 那是...
that's my son.
那是我的儿子
Why aren't you at home with them
为什么你不在家陪他们
instead of hanging around with reindeer boy?
而是跟驯鹿小孩在这?
One time long ago...
很久以前...
it... it was a cold winter, and the little one was hungry,
那... 那是一个寒冬 我儿子饿了
so I went out to find food.
因此我出去找点食物
When I came back, they were all gone...
当我回来时 他们全部不见了...
Aunt Sally, my wife, my son.
萨莉姑母 我的妻子 我的孩子
In the snow were tracks.
在雪里有脚印
Wolf tracks.
野狼脚印
Oh, I'm so sorry, Nutboy.
噢 我非常抱歉 松果男孩
I... I didn't know.
我... 我不知道是这样
Niko's my family now...
现在尼科是我的家人...
at least until he finds his real dad.
至少直到他找到 他真正的爸爸
What about you?
你怎么样?
Do you have a family?
你有家人吗?
Yeah, sort of.
是的 算是有
Sort of?
算是有?
Truth is,
事实是
my family didn't want me to be a singer,
我的家人不想要我 成为一位歌手
but I was young and restless,
但是我那时年轻气盛
so, uh, I ran away from home.
因此 噢 我离家出走
I've been away for years.
我离家出走多年了
I know what it's like
我知道那种感觉
to be on your own.
凡事都得靠自己
Huh?
啊?
I had a dream.
我有做个梦
I dreamt that Black Wolf attacked the herd and ate Mom...
我梦见那匹布莱克野狼 攻击鹿群且把妈妈吃掉了...
and Saga.
以及传说
It's just a nightmare, Niko.
它只是个恶梦 尼科
It wasn't your fault the wolves attacked the herd.
野狼攻击鹿群这不是你的错
Nobody blames you.
没人责备你
How do you know?
你怎样知道?
If Julius says so, then it's true.
如果朱利尔斯这样说 那么它就是真的
Huh?
啊?
Wow!
哇!
# Well, there's something that I want to say #
# 好的 我有某些事想要说 #
# And there's something that I've got to do #
# 和我有某些事必须做 #
# Even got down on my knees to pray #
# 甚至下跪祈祷 #
# 'Cause, baby, I miss you #
# 因为 宝贝 我想念你 #
# Oooohhhh! # Yeah!
哦! 耶!
Gentlemen, I give you... Santa's Fell!
各位先生 让我介绍... 耶诞老人之家!
We did it! Yay!
我们成功了! 哇!
- Whoo-hoo! Whoo!  - Come on!
- 喔! 喔!  - 快来呀!
We have to hurry! It's Christmas Day tomorrow!
我们必须赶快! 明天就是耶诞节!
The entrance to Santa's Fell,
耶诞老人家的入口
said to be haunted and full of deadly traps at every turn.
据说里面鬼魂出没 且处处充满陷阱
No one who has gone in there has made it back out alive.
进入那里的人 没有人活着出来
Cool!
真酷!
Last one in is a chicken!
最后一个是小鸡!
Hey!
喂!
Hey, shh!
喂 嘘!
Here's the secret shortcut.
这是个秘密的捷径
Whoa, whoa.
哇 哇
We haven't been very lucky with shortcuts,
我们从未幸运走过捷径
so in my considered opinion...
因此在我考虑后...
You didn't hear my considered opinion!
你们都没听到我考虑后的想法!
After you, marshmallow.
你先请 小软糖
Ohh!
哦!
But... I thought I was your lucky charm.
但是... 我以为我是你的幸运符
You are.
你是
If there are any surprises in there,
如果那里有任何惊奇
you get them first.
你会第一个得到
Lucky for us!
为我们带个好运!
I'll go first, boss.
我先走 头家
Huh?
嗯?
I'm going to miss you, Specs.
我会想念你 史贝斯
Watch the step, guys.
小伙子 小心
That's it!
够了!
Niko, I'm not letting you go one step further.
尼科 我不让你再踏台阶了
You go on, Wilma.
你继续 威尔玛
Find his dad and tell him the boy says hello.
找到他的爸爸告诉他 他儿子向他问好
Niko and me will stay right here.
尼科和我就留在这里
Nothing to be afraid of. Ice can't hurt me.
没有什么害怕 冰不能伤害我
Ice is nice.
冰是好的
Nice ice.
好的冰
Move it.
移动它
Oh! Unh! Ohh!
噢! 啊! 啊!
Aah!
啊!
Specs!
史贝斯!
Look out!
小心!
Thanks.
感谢
Uhn!
嗯!
Boys.
男孩
This is it... the place where dreams come true.
这里... 就是梦想实现的地方
Wow.
哇
Up there is Santa's factory.
上面就是耶诞老人的工厂了
Look at that!
看那!
And that's the Flying Forces airport.
那就是飞行团队的机场
Wow.
哇
Dad! I'm gonna meet Dad!
爸爸! 我将要见到爸爸!
You know, Niko,
你知道 尼科
people aren't always exactly the way you think they are.
人们不总是 正好是想的那样
I know exactly what Dad is... a hero!
我确切知道爸爸是什么... 一名英雄!
No, but he...
不 但是他...
What Nutboy's trying to say is, well...
松果男孩想说的是 嗯...
Sometimes heroes turn out to be just like everyone else.
有时英雄正如其他人一样
My dad's not like everyone else.
我的爸爸和别人不一样
Maybe we should come back after Christmas!
或许我们应该在耶诞节之后回来!
- Niko!  - Ohh...
- 尼科!  - 哦...
Wait.
等一下
Wow!
哇!
Stay sharp, men.
保持敏锐 老兄
Christmas is no time for fun.
耶诞节可没时间开玩笑
Well, it is, but you know what I mean.
嗯 是的 但是你们知道我的意思
Uh, Dasher...
噢 气宇轩昂...
I'm not in the mood for interruptions, Comet.
我不想要被打搅 彗星来说
- But Dasher!  - You too, Blitzen.
- 但是气宇轩昂!  - 你也是 闪电
Reindeer on the runway!
驯鹿们在跑道上降落!
- That has got to hurt.  - Nice work, guys.
- 那一定很疼  - 干得好 小伙子
We almost broke Santa.
我们差点害死耶诞老人
Hey, what's the bright idea, kid, standing on the runway?
喂 孩子站在跑道上做什?
Are you trying to ruin Christmas?
你想毁了耶诞节吗?
N-n-no.
并不
I... my dad. I wanted to...
我... 我的爸爸 我想要...
Do you have any idea who we are?
你知道我们是谁吗?
Of course he does! Everybody knows the Flying Forces.
他当然知道! 每人都知道飞行团队
# We're reindeer, we're not horses #
# 我们是驯鹿 我们不是马 #
# We're Santa's Flying Forces! Ho ho! #
# 我们是耶诞老人的飞行团队的! 后 后! #
All right, that's enough!
好 够了!
Christmas is right on top of us. C-Day. I won't tolerate sloppiness.
耶诞节迫在眉睫决不容忍马马唬唬
One slipup like that tomorrow, and we're all out of a job!
明天在出现那样失误 我们会全部失业的!
- Yeah, right.  - What's funny?
- 是的 是  - 有什么好笑的?
- We can't get fired!  - We're irreplaceable!
- 我们不能被解雇!  - 我们是不可取代!
We're the Flying Forces!
我们是飞行团队!
# We're reindeer, we're not horses #
# 我们是驯鹿 我们不是马 #
# We're Santa's Flying Forces! Ho ho! #
# 我们是耶诞老人的飞行团队! 后后! #
Guys, guys, guys, seriously, it's starting to get annoying.
伙计们 伙计们 伙计们 我说认真的 别开始惹恼我了
Now, let's just hear the kid out.
现在 让我们听孩子把话说完
Yeah! Yeah!
是! 是!
The... the wolves!
野狼!
They want to eat you... and Santa.
他们想要吃掉你们... 以及耶诞老人
Thanks, kid, but there's nothing to worry about.
孩子 感谢 但是没有什么要担心的
No wolf has ever made it through the labyrinth.
没有野狼穿过迷宫到这里
- But...  - Why don't you come...
- 但是...  - 你为什么不来...
...and get that imagination something to drink in the mess hall, ja?
...到食堂吃点什么?
Incorrigible.
无可救药
Well? What are you waiting for?
好吗? 你在等什么?
Hello?
你好吗?
Here speaks Donner. We're needing more barley brew. Over.
我是唐纳 我们正需要更多的大麦啤完毕
For crying out loud! Again?
哎呀! 声音大点?
- That's yours!  - Ja.
- 那是你的!  - 啊
Hey, guys, guys, listen up.
喂 伙计们 伙计们 听我说
I just thought of something.
某些事情 我刚刚想
Nobody can get through the ice labyrinth, right?
没人能透过 冰迷宫 是吗?
- Mm-hmm.  - Ahh!
- 嗯噢  - 啊!
So how did the kid get here?
那么孩子怎样到达这里的?
- Um, well, I...  - Hello, boys!
- 嗯 嗯...  - 你好 男孩!
Wilma!
威尔玛!
Okay, boys, have I got a song for you!
好 伙计们 我有首歌要送你们!
Wunderbar! I love music!
太好啦! 我喜欢音乐!
Bring it on!
开始吧!
Hit it!
踩它!
# Ba-dum, ba-dum, ba-dum, ba-dum, ba-dum #
# 吧 吧 吧 吧 吧 吧 #
Mm mm mm mm!
嗯 嗯 嗯 嗯!
# Ba-dum, ba-dum, ba-dum, ba-dum, ba-dum #
# 吧 吧 吧 吧 吧 吧 #
# Hello, fellas #
# 你好的 伙计们 #
# We know you're heroes and you can fly so high #
# 我们知道你们是英雄 并且你能飞越如此高的 #
# You all make Christmas a special time #
# 你们使耶诞节变成特别的时刻 #
# Now one of you will get a surprise #
# 现在你们中的一员 将得到一个惊奇 #
# Yeah, a real big surprise #
# 是的 真正的大惊奇 #
That's what I'm saying!
那是我正说的!
# Is it Dasher, so strong and wise? #
# 是它气宇轩昂 如此强大和聪明吗? #
# Or is it cutie Cupid with his dreamy eyes? #
# 或者它漂亮丘比特 由於他的梦一般眼睛吗? #
# Is it Vixen or even Blitzen? #
# 是它悍妇还是甚至闪电吗? #
# Come on, Prancer, don't you tell me no lies #
# 来吧 烈马 别对我说谎 #
# Listen, fellas, this boy has come a long way today #
# 听着 伙计 这个男孩 走了很长的路到这里 #
# And one of you shares the same DNA #
# 而你们之一 和他血脉相同 #
The what?
什么?
# Yeah, one of you is Niko's daddy #
# 是的 你们其中一个是尼科的爸爸 #
The what?!
什么?!
# So tell me who is Niko's daddy #
# 因此告诉我谁是尼科的爸爸 #
She's right.
她说的对
One of you is my dad.
你们中有一个是我的爸爸
Do any of you remember taking a young lady reindeer flying one Christmas?
你们中有任何人记得有一年耶诞节 带着一位年轻的女士驯鹿在天上飞吗?
- Yeah!  - Yeah, right.
- 是!  - 是的 是
Sorry, kid, this is the world famous Flying Forces you're dealing with.
抱歉 孩子 你正在和世界闻名 飞越团队打交道
- We're gonna need more details.  - # We're reindeer, we're not horses #
- 我们需要更多的细节  - # 我们是驯鹿 我们不是马 #
# We're Santa's Flying Forces! Ho ho! #
# 我们是耶诞老人的飞行团队! 后后! #
Flying Fools, if you ask me.
你问我 就是一些会飞的傻瓜
- Her name was Oona.  - Oona?
- 她的名字是乌纳  - 乌纳吗?
From Home Valley.
来自山谷
- Nah.  - Doesn't ring a bell.
- 不记得  - 没印象
I was so sure.
我如此确信
Santa's Flying Forces. Ha!
耶诞老人的飞行团队  哈!
None of you deserve to be this boy's father!
你们都不配当 这个男孩父亲!
Come on, Niko. We don't need these guys.
尼科 跟我来 我们不需要这些人
There is one way we can settle this.
有一种方法 我们能解决这问题
The ability to fly is only passed from father to son.
飞的能力只能父子相传
If Niko can fly, then we'll know one of us is his father.
如果尼科能飞 我们将知道 我们其中一个是他的父亲
So, guys, what do you think?
因此 伙计们 你认为怎么样?
The flying test, the flying test!
飞行试验 飞行试验!
The flying test!
飞行试验!
Y-y-you don't have to do this, Niko.
嗯 嗯 你不必做这 尼科
There are many other ways of finding out who your dad is.
有很多方法 找出你的爸爸是谁
Like what?
哦 哪方面?
Like... like...
比如... 比如...
I know I can fly, Julius, just like you always said!
我知道我能飞 朱利尔斯 正如你总是说一样!
Don't worry, Julius. It'll be okay.
朱利尔斯 不要担心 没事的
Imagine you're a shooting star in the sky.
想像你是 在天空里的一颗流星
Don't give in to your fear.
不要对你的恐惧让步
If you get scared, your power of flight disappears.
如果你感到害怕 你的飞行能力就会消失
You're not here to fall, Niko. You're here to fly.
你不在这里跌倒 尼科 你在这里是要飞起来的
- Let's do it!  - You can do it.
- 让我们开始!  - 你能做到的
- You can do it! Go on!  - Go on, boy!
- 你能做到的! 快点!  - 男孩 加油!
- All right!  - Go, kid.
- 好!  - 孩子 去吧
No!
不!
I'm not letting you do this.
我不能让你这么做
You mean you don't believe I can do it.
你意思是你不相信 我能飞
Yes. No... I mean, you almost died at the River of Certain Doom.
是的 不... 我的意思是 你差点死在审判河上
What if you're not so lucky this time?
如果你这次不如此运气好 怎么办?
I don't need your help, Julius.
我不需要你的帮助 朱利尔斯
Unh.
啊
Uhh!
啊!
Hey, y...
喂...
Believe you can, and you will fly.
相信自己能做到 你就能飞
- Believe you can, and you will fly!  - No!
- 相信自己能做到 你就能飞!  - 不!
Believe you can, and you will fly!
你能相信 并且你将飞!
No!
不!
Oh, no!
噢 不!
Niko! Niko!
尼科! 尼科!
Ohh.
喔
Niko! Are you hurt?
尼科! 你受伤了吗?
You were right, Julius.
你说的对 朱利尔斯
I couldn't do it.
我不能做到
Whew! Well, he tried.
哎呀! 嗯 他试过了
Don't feel bad, kid.
别难过 孩子
Wilma, take this brave boy back to his home.
威尔玛 带这个勇敢的男孩 回到他的家
I guess my dad wasn't one of Santa's reindeer.
我猜测我的爸爸不是 耶诞老人的一头驯鹿
He was just a coward like me.
他和我一样是一个懦夫
I know it feels bad, Niko,
我知道你很难过 尼科
but when we're back home, things will look better!
但是等我们回家 事情将看起来更好!
I don't want to go back home.
我不想要回家
I wanted to fly.
我想要飞
You always said you believed I could do it, but you lied!
你总是说你相信 我能做到 但是你骗我!
I was just being cautious.
我只是比较谨慎
You didn't want me to come here.
你不想要我来这里
Of course I did!
我当然希望你来这里!
You didn't want me to find Dad!
你不想要我找到爸爸!
- Niko...  - You didn't want me to fly.
- 尼科...  - 你也不想要我飞
- ...lower your voice.  - Guys!
- ...小声点  - 小伙子!
You ruined everything!
你把一切都搞杂了!
- I forbid you to...  - You can't forbid me anything.
- 我禁止你...  - 你不能因任何事情而禁止我
You're not my dad.
你不是我的爸爸
I never want to see you again!
我再也不想要再见你了!
Niko, wait!
尼科 等等!
Ha!
哈!
Nutboy means well. He's just...
松果男孩出於善意 他只不过...
Huh?
嗯?
- Wolves!  - Oh, no!
- 野狼!  - 噢 不!
Hurry!
赶快!
Go!
Wolves!
狼来了!
The wolves are here!
野狼找到这了!
Now, Niko, I told you no wolf has ever...
现在 尼科 我告诉你 没有野狼有...
Wolf!
狼来了!
Men, assume flying positions.
老兄 假装飞越位置
There's a new Santa in town!
在城里来了一个新耶诞老人!
Why don't they fly away?
他们为什么不飞走?
They're too scared. They've lost the belief.
他们太惊吓 他们已经失去信心
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey, nice wolf.
哼! 喂 喂 喂 野狼大哥
Come on. Hey, hey, hey, down boy.
跟我来 喂 喂 喂 往身上打
Not the face, not the face!
别打脸 别打脸!
Dooh! Uhhh.
咚! 啊
Christmas dinner is served!
耶诞节晚餐已准备好!
Bwaaggh!
啊!
You!
你!
You're supposed to be dead!
你死定了!
I'll give you something to laugh about!
我让你再笑!
Aaaaahhhhh!
啊!
Bwaaahhhrrr!
哇!
Niko?
尼科?
# Have a happy Christmastime #
# 圣诞快乐 #
# Have a happy, happy... #
# 快乐的 快乐的... #
Help! Santa! The wolves are here!
救命! 耶诞老人! 野狼在这里!
You've reached Santa's Hotline.
你已经拨通耶诞老人的热线
If you've been nice all year and want to leave a wish list,
如果你一年都乖乖的 那么
please press one.
就许个愿吧
If you've been naughty,
如果你顽皮
please hold and one of our elf operators will be with you shortly.
那么我们的小精灵 马上就会接你的电话
Please state the nature of your naughtiness.
说说你为何顽皮
Oh... kay.
噢... 嗯
No presents for you this year.
你今年收不到礼物了
Rrrraaaahhhh!
啊啊!
- Wow, a teddy bear!  - Wow!
- 哇 一头玩具熊!  - 哇!
Lucky you!
你真走运!
Hey, reindeer boy.
喂 小驯鹿
Know how we catch squirrels in the summer?
知道我们夏天怎样抓住松鼠吗?
Aah!
啊!
Leave him alone!
住手!
Don't worry, Niko! I'll take care of him.
不要担心! 尼科 我来搞定他
Aaahhhh!
啊啊!
Julius!
朱利尔斯!
Ohh!
哦!
- Niko!  - Just relax, Prancer.
- 尼科!  - 放松点 烈马
- This is good, this is good.  - Come on!
- 很好 很好  - 拜托!
- Your face is fine...  - You gotta help him!
- 你很帅...  - 你必须帮助他!
You can fly!
你能飞!
I can't see them... so they can't see me.
我不能看见他们... 因此他们不能看见我
Oh, grr!
噢 额!
No one to help you now, reindeer boy!
没有人现在帮助你 小驯鹿!
Huh?
嗯?
Whoooaaaa!
哇!
Huh?
阿?
Hey, come back here, you coward! I wasn't finished.
喂 回到这 你这个懦夫! 我还没玩完
Oompf!
喔!
Oohhh!
噢啊!
Unh!
嗯!
Ooonkh!
噢!
Niko needs help! Save him!
尼科需要帮助! 快去救他!
We... we can't even save ourselves.
我们... 我们甚至不能救自己
That boy braved rivers, wolves, and blizzards to meet you,
那个男孩不怕河 野狼 大风雪 来见你们
the Flying Forces.
飞行团队
He thought you were the bravest, most heroic reindeer in the world.
他认为你是最勇敢的 在世界上的大多数英雄驯鹿
He believed in you!
他那么相信你们!
Well? Was he wrong?
好吗? 他错误吗?
Are you the world famous Flying Forces
你们还是世界闻名的 飞越团队
who never give up, no matter what,
不论发生什么 都从未放弃的 飞鹿吗
or... or just a bunch of frightened... horses?
或者... 或者只不过一群... 害怕吓破胆的马?
Aah!
啊!
We're reindeer, we're not horses.
我们是驯鹿 我们不是马
We're Santa's Flying Forces.
我们是耶诞老人的飞行团队
Ho, ho!
何!
Aah!
啊!
Ha ha ha!
哈哈哈!
Aaaaahhhhhh...
啊啊...
...ooohhh!
...噢!
Niko!
尼科!
Julius!
朱利尔斯!
Aah!
啊!
Hold on, Niko!
尼科 稍等!
Men, Santa Speed!
同志们 耶诞老人速度!
End of the line for you, reindeer boy.
是时候解决你了 小驯鹿
Julius! No!
朱利尔斯! 不!
- I've always believed in you, Niko.  - Aah!
- 我总是相信你 尼科  - 啊!
Julius!
朱利尔斯!
Aaaahhhh!
啊!
At least I won't go on an empty stomach!
至少我不会饿着肚子!
Leave him alone!
放开他!
Rrraaaawwwrrrr!
啊!
You did, it Niko! You can fly!
你做到了 尼科! 你能飞!
You can fly!
你能飞!
Yahoo!
ㄚ呼
Huh?
哈?
Boss...
头家...
What do we do now?
现在我们怎么办?
Who needs reindeer when you've got moss?
当你有苔藓时 谁需要驯鹿?
Rahhh!
啊!
Raahhh! Raahhh!
啊! 啊!
Hey, you wanna go see if there are some leftovers in Santa's kitchen?
喂 你想不想要看看耶诞老人的厨房 是否有一些剩馀物吗?
That sounds like the best Christmas present ever.
那听上去是 最好的耶诞礼物
Hey, kid.
嗨 孩子
Good work.
做的好
Thanks.
谢谢
Uh, Prancer, is it?
噢 烈性的马 是吗?
Well, actually, you can... you can call me...
嗯 实际上 你能... 你能叫我...
...Dad.
...爸爸
- You're... you're my dad?  - Whoa, whoa!
- 你是... 你是我的爸爸吗?  - 嗯 嗯!
Yeah. I... I guess so.
是的 我... 大概是的
Wow.
哇
Hey, fellas, a big cheer for my son, the hero!
喂 伙计们为我的儿子 欢呼吧 小英雄!
Hey!
嗨!
# For he's a jolly good reindeer #
# 他是非常快乐的小驯鹿 #
Nice one, son.
不错 儿子
Ho, ho, ho, men, Santa's ready!
喉 喉 喉 兄弟们 耶诞老人准备好了!
Oh, wow!
噢 哇!
So, you must be Niko.
嗯 你一定是尼科
Uh, yes, sir.
噢 是的 先生
I hear you've had quite a time.
我听说你很了不起
I've had a word with the boys,
我已经和他们谈过了
and they tell me you may be able to do me a little favor.
他们告诉我你愿意 帮我一点忙
Huh?
啊?
Oh, wow.
噢 哇
Look at the boy. He really did it.
看这孩子 他真的做到了
Huh.
哎
You were pretty heroic yourself, Julius.
你相当勇敢阿 朱利尔斯
I kinda like "Nutboy."
我只是个松果男孩
Aww.
啊
Listen, kid, I'm sorry about earlier...
听我说 孩子 很抱歉我应该早点...
you know, not telling you right away.
你知道 应该早点告诉你
I guess I was...
我觉得我有点...
Scared?
害怕吗?
No. No, no, no.
不 不 不 不
Santa's reindeer don't get scared.
耶诞老人的驯鹿不害怕的
When Christmas is over, Dad, we can go back to the herd
爸爸 我想 当耶诞节结束时 我们能回到鹿群
and you'll meet Mom again... and Grandpa!
并且你将再次见到妈妈... 以及爷爷!
And we can all live together!
我们能生活在一起了!
Oh, of course, that'd be just great,
噢 当然 太好了
but we need to practice flying every day.
但是我们需要每天练飞行
You know, race over the Alps, shoot up to the moon.
你知道飞行在阿尔卑斯山上方的比赛 飞到月亮
But what about after all that?
还有呢?
After all that, we'll have even more fun!
以后所有 我们将有更多的开心!
Sing reindeer songs, play reindeer games!
唱驯鹿歌 玩法驯鹿比赛!
And boogie the night away!
以及离开的Boogie夜晚!
# Unh unh unh unh unh-unh #
# 啊 啊 啊 啊 啊 #
- Funky!  - Yah, mon.
- 胆战心惊!  - 嗳呀
I have to go back home now, Niko.
我必须现在回家 尼科
I'll tell your mother you're all right.
我会告诉你的母亲你们很好
Huh?
啊?
I know you'll be the best reindeer on the Flying Forces.
我知道你将是最好的驯鹿 在飞行团队时
Julius, wait!
朱利尔斯 等等!
Just like you always dreamed of!
要好好为理想奋斗!
No, Julius! Come back!
不 朱利尔斯! 回来!
Goodbye...
再见...
...son.
...儿子
No...
不...
Why did he leave, Wilma?
威尔玛 他为什么离开?
I have a feeling he didn't want to get in the way.
我有一种感觉 他不想要碍事
I'm telling the truth!
我正说真话!
Niko can fly and has joined Santa's Flying Forces!
尼科能飞并且已经参加 耶诞老人的飞行团队!
We don't have time for your stories, Julius.
我们没有时间 对你的故事来说 朱利尔斯
They don't put food in our mouths.
我们从未见过他们
I trusted you to bring my boy back!
我还相信你会带我的孩子回来!
Uhh.
嗯
I believe you, Julius.
我相信你 朱利尔斯
Do you think Niko's happy?
你认为尼科愉快吗?
Sure. I've never seen him so happy.
当然 我从未看见他如此愉快
Yeehaw!
耶噢!
- Hey!  - What?
- 喂!  - 什么?
What's that up there?
在那里向上的那个是什么?
- What on earth is that?  - It's Niko!
- 那个究竟是什么?  - 是尼科!
Wahoo!
啊哈!
Niko?
尼科吗?
- Niko can fly!  - Huh?
- 尼科能飞!  - 啊?
Whoa! Niko can fly!
哇! 尼科能飞!
Niko! My little boy!
尼科! 我的小男孩!
Mom! Not in front of everybody.
妈妈! 不要在每人的面前
What happened? Are you all right?
怎么回事? 你好吗?
Where have you been!
你到那里了!
I'm sorry I ran away, Mom.
妈妈 对不起我跑了
Niko? Why aren't you with the Flying Forces?
尼科吗? 为什么你没和飞行团队一起?
Uh, because, well...
噢 因为 好...
And they let you fly off on your own?
他们让你 独立飞走吗?
Those irresponsible, good-for-nothing...
那些无责任感的 一无是处...
# We're Santa's Flying Forces! Ho ho! #
# 我们是耶诞老人的飞行团队 后 后! #
It's them!
是他们!
I never thought I'd see the day.
我从未认为我将看见这天
Make it snappy, boys!
男孩 快点!
As a token of our gratitude for saving our lives,
为救我们的生命 作为我们报答之恩
Julius the Flying Squirrel will from now on be
朱利尔斯今后是 飞行松鼠
an honorary member of Santa's Flying Forces.
也是一名光荣的 耶诞老人的飞行团队
- What?  - Ja, ja! Excellent!
- 什么?  - 啊 啊! 真好!
Okay, men, come on!
好 兄弟们 跟我来!
# He's a squirrel, not a hamster #
# 他是一只松鼠 并非一只仓鼠 #
# A hero, not a prankster! Ho ho! #
# 一名英雄 并非一个捣蛋鬼! 后 后! #
Thanks, guys.
小伙子 谢谢
That's... almost too much.
那是... 太过奖了
Yes, well, it is, but, what the heck, it's Christmas!
是的 嗯 它 但是 管它呢 今天是耶诞节!
Hey, Niko, you coming with us?
嗨 尼科你与我们一起来?
I went all the way to Santa's Fell to find my dad,
我一路走 开始找到我的爸爸 对於耶诞老人来说
but then I realized he was with me all along.
然而我意识到 他始终和我在一起
I'm staying here.
我要留在这里
Aw.
啊
But... maybe I could come visit you after Christmas, if...
但是... 或许我能来 在耶诞节之后拜访你 如果如果...
if that's okay.
如果那是好的
Yeah, and I could teach you vertical takeoffs and backward flips.
是的 我能教你 垂直的起飞和向后飞
Hmm.
噢
Well, I mean, if that's okay with, uh, your mom.
嗯 我的意思是 噢 你的妈妈 同意的话
Merry Christmas, Niko.
耶诞快乐 尼科
Let's get this show on the road, boys!
让我们得到这场演出 在道路上 孩子!
Ho ho ho!
吼 吼!
Ah.
啊
Hi, Niko.
喂 尼科
Mmmmwah!
嗯哇!
Whoa!
哼!
Over here! Plenty of food and water.
在这里! 足够的食物和水
What did I tell ya?
我经常告诉你的?
I always said the boy could fly!
我总是说这孩子能飞!
Yay!
耶!
Yeehaw!
耶噢!
Niko, slow down!
尼科 减速!
Don't ever do that again.
别这样了
What the heck, do it again! Do it again!
管它呢 再来一次! 再来一次!
Yahoo!
ㄚ呼
# Winter snow and ice between us #
# 冬天的雪和冰来临 #
# Keeping us so far apart #
# 让我们分隔万里 #
# In the stars I'll find the answers #
# 我内心的疑问 #
# To the questions of my heart #
# 终於迎刃而解 #
# Moonlight on the snow that whispers #
# 雪地里的月光轻轻诉说 #
# Falling through the silent night #
# 在这安静的夜晚降落 #
# Like the stars so far above me #
# 就像远在天边的星星 #
# I know your love shines so bright #
# 我知道你的爱多么闪耀 #
# Can you show me, can you show me #
# 你能不能能不能指引我 #
# Can you show me the way to the stars? #
# 寻找星星的道路? #
# Will you take me, will you take me #
# 你会不会会不会带着我 #
# Will you take me away to the stars? #
# 一起去寻找星星? #
# Through the cold and stormy weather #
# 寒冷和狂风也无法阻止 #
# Far across the mountains high #
# 我跨越高山 #
# Through the forests, over oceans #
# 森林和海洋也无法阻止 #
# Your love guides me like a light #
# 你的爱为我照明 #
# Can you show me, can you show me #
# 你能不能能不能指引我 #
# Can you show me the way to the stars? #
# 寻找星星的道路? #
# Will you take me, will you take me #
# 你会不会会不会带着我 #
# Will you take me away? #
# 一起去寻找星星? #
# Can you show me #
# 你能不能指引我 #
# Can you show me the way to the stars? #
# 寻找星星的道路? #
www.ispeaken.com
史上最值得看的50部英语动画片